- Hey, guys. - Hey.
- 嗨，大家 - 嗨！
Honey, I got us that room at the Woodford Inn this weekend.
親愛的，這週末我有訂到那個六福飯店
That place in Vermont? You can take a hint.
就是在佛蒙特的? 我的暗示果然有用!!
You can't go away this weekend. It's Emma's birthday.
你們這周未不能外出啊 那天是艾瑪生日
We're having a party.
會有一個派對
Can't you have the party when we get back?
能不能等我們回來再舉辦呢?
No. It won't be her real birthday.
那就會很怪，等於不是她真正的生日
Gee, if only she were 1 and had no idea what the hell a birthday was.
喔，更何況她才一歲 也不知道生日到底是什麼
Come on, you guys, this is really important to us.
嘿，這對我們很重要呢
Sorry, but Chandler and I could really use a weekend away..
喔，很抱歉，我和錢德 希望一起度過假日
- you know, to reconnect, emotionally. - There's this thing I really want us to do.
- 我們想溝通溝通，心理上的 - 我們從以前就很想做這件事
I read about it in Maxim.
我在 Maxim 雜誌看到的
Well, can't you just go to Vermont the next day?
你們可以選擇其他日子吧?
Yeah, we want everyone to be there.
我們非常希望大家都能來...
As much as I hate to delay your doing weird sex stuff to my little sister.
跟我非常討厭你對我妹做 那奇怪的「性」事，一樣多
And, I mean, you know, you guys, this is a big deal.
聽著，這是一件大事呢
How can we have her first birthday party without her aunt and her uncle?
他不能度過他的一歲生日 如果沒有他阿姨和叔叔陪他
I promise I won't do any magic.
我保證我絕對不會表演魔術的
All right, we'll stay. We can just drive up after the party.
好的，我們會留下來 還是可以趕過去
Fine. But if we end up not doing this Maxim thing because of this party..
如果派對的事情害 我們沒做雜誌上的事情--
Believe me, that is not why we won't be doing that.
那不是理由，好不好?
One With The Cake
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
You know, Phoebe, when I was little, on my birthday..
你知道嗎，菲比 小的時候... 在我的生日那天...
my daddy would hide a present in every room of the house.
我爸會在家裡每個房間藏禮物
And then he would draw a treasure map to help me find them all.
然後會給我們「寶藏地圖」 叫我們自己找
I love family traditions like that.
喔，我喜歡這種家庭習俗
When Ursula and I were kids, on our birthday..
但小時候，在我生日 我繼父...
our stepdad would sell his blood to buy us food.
...會去賣他的血 來買吃的
- Hey, guys. - Hi.
- 嗨，大家 - 嗨
- I brought the camera for Emma's video. - Oh, good!
- 我帶了攝像機，來錄艾瑪的派對 - 喔，好呢
We had this idea to make a birthday video for Emma..
我們想要錄艾瑪的派對
- and we'll give it to her when she's 18. - Oh, cool.
- 當她十八歲時，再拿給他看 - 喔，酷
- Wow, it's like a time capsule. - Yeah.
- 就像一個「時空膠囊」 - 是啊
Oh, just think, she's gonna be watching that video on a TV..
想像一下，到時 她就會在一個當前未發明
that hasn't even been invented yet..
的電視機上來看這個影帶
with friends who, right now, are just, like, babies.
和朋友， 當前跟她一樣還是個嬰兒， 一起看
And they'll be living in a floating city that the humans built..
然後，我們住在一個浮起來的城市...
to escape the ant people.
...為了逃避螞蟻人
That's the hope.
希望是如此!!
- So is Emma awake yet? - No, it's still naptime.
- 所以，艾瑪起來了嗎? - 沒有，現在午睡時間
- But she'll be up soon. - Where's Joey?
- 不過，馬上他就會醒了 - 喬伊在哪裡呢?
I said, it's still naptime.
我說過了，現在是午睡時間
- Hey, there's Uncle Joey. - Hey.
- 嗨，來看看喬伊叔叔吧 - 嘿！
Hey, say something to Emma on her 18th birthday.
說句話，給十八歲生日的艾瑪吧
- Eighteen, huh? - Joey, no!
- 十八歲，哈? - 嘿，喬伊，不要--
What? What? It's for her hot friends.
怎麼啦，怎麼啦 ? 是要給艾瑪很辣的朋友
When they see this, you'll be 52.
當他看到這個，你已經是五十二歲了
And starting to think about settling down.
就是我開始穩定下來的時候呢
Joey, will you please set this up for people to put Emma's presents on?
喬伊，可以幫我打開嗎? 這樣就可以放艾瑪的禮物
Love to. Yeah.
喔，非常願意呢
- We were supposed to bring presents? - Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
- 我們要給他禮物嗎? - 是啊。我寫了一首歌給艾瑪
Oh, yeah. How was I supposed to know?
那，我怎麼會知道呢?
- Joey, it's a birthday party. - Yeah, but for a 1-year-old.
- 這是一個生日派對呢 -是啊，但她僅一歲而已
What's the point? The other day she laughed for an hour at a cup.
重點在哪裡? 那天她對著杯子大笑一個多小時
Just a cup with a picture of Elmo on it, dressed as a farmer.
只是一個普通杯子 上面有阿母的農夫圖案
And he's standing next to this cow, and the cow says, "El-moo."
阿母站在牛旁邊 牛說了：阿母-母-母-母
Man, that's a funny cup.
真是好笑的杯子
- Hey. - Hey.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Where's the birthday girl? - Oh, she's still napping.
- 生日的女主角呢? - 她還在睡覺呢
She was probably up all night excited about the party she knows is happening.
喔，當然，他昨晚知道要辦一個派對... ...就太興奮了，睡不著
I know you guys really want to get to Vermont, and this isn't a big deal to you.
我知道，你們很想去佛蒙特 對你們也是一件大事
But it really is to us, okay? Emma will never have a first birthday again.
但這對我們也是一件大事，好嗎? 艾瑪不會再有第二次的一週歲生日
You're right. We're sorry.
好的，你對，我們很抱歉
Let's wake up Emma and get the fun time started!
那把艾瑪叫醒，開始派對吧!!
She didn't sleep well last night, so we can't wake her.
她昨晚睡不好所以我們不能叫醒她
Are you frigging kidding me, Greene?
你是不是在跟我開玩笑啊， 姓格林的!!
- Hi! - Hey!
- 嗨 - 嗨
- I'm so glad you came. - I can't believe Emma's already 1.
- 很高興你來了 - 真不敢相信，艾瑪已經一歲了
I remember your first birthday.
我還記得你的一歲生日
Ross was jealous of all the attention we were giving you.
羅斯很羨慕我們給你的一切
He pulled on his testicles so hard..
他很用力的去拉他的蛋蛋
we had to take him to the emergency room.
所以我們要帶他去看急診
There's something you didn't know about your dad.
有些關於你爸爸的事情你還不知道
Hey, Mr. and Mrs. Geller. Let me help you with that.
嗨，蓋勒先生和太太 我幫你放下來吧
- Thank you. - Oh, man, this is great, huh?
- 謝謝 - 見到你們真好
The three of us together again. You know what would be fun?
我們三個又聚在一起 你知道更有趣的事嗎?
If we gave this present to Emma from all of us.
就當做這禮物是我們三個人一起送給艾瑪的，怎樣?
Which one are you?
你是哪一位啊?
- I can't believe Emma's still asleep. - I know. What are we gonna do?
- 真不敢相信，艾瑪還在睡 - 我知道，但沒轍兒啊
I've got a plan. I've got a plan.
我有計劃，一個好計劃
I'm going to ram this platter really hard into your ribs.
我會把這個鐵盤 很用力的砸到你身上
You're gonna scream out, and that'll wake her up.
那你會痛的哇哇大叫 這樣會吵醒她，對不對?
I'm not going to Vermont with this Monica.
我不會和這種莫妮卡去佛蒙特的
Hey, Phoebe? You know what?
嗨，菲比，你知道嗎?
I was thinking since you wrote a song..
即然你寫了歌給艾瑪
maybe I could do something for Emma using my talents.
那我也可以給艾瑪表演我的才藝?
So you're gonna hit on her?
所以，你要去泡艾瑪，是不是?
No, no, no. My talents as an actor.
不是，不是啦 我的才藝是演戲
You know, I could, like, maybe..
我可能，可以--
I could do a dramatic reading of one of her books.
給她邊讀本書邊演出來
Or you could stick a fork in an apple.
或是，你可以把一個叉子叉在蘋果上?
- Hey, I think Emma might like it. - Oh, Emma might like what?
- 嘿，我想艾瑪會喜歡呢! -喔，艾瑪會喜歡什麼?
- My present. - What did you get her?
- 我的禮物! -你要給她什麼?
- We prepared performances. - Separate performances.
- 實際上，我們正準備一個表演 - 分開的的表演呢
But equally real.
但是差不多
That sounds like fun.
喔，聽起來好好玩了
People are getting a little antsy waiting for Emma to wake up from her nap.
你知道嗎？ 因為大家有點不耐煩要等艾瑪起來...
So would you mind performing them once now?
...所以，你們可以現在表演一個嗎?
- Sure, yeah! - Okay.
- 當然可以 - 好--好，那好吧
Okay. All right. Everybody, let's get this party started.
大家聽著，我們開始吧
Joey and Phoebe are gonna perform a little something for us.
喬伊和菲比要表演給大家看呢
Oh, great.
喔，太好了
Aren't you gonna be embarrassed having nothing prepared?
那你會不會覺丟臉 還沒準備就上去表演呢?
I do it every week with three cameras pointed at me and a whole crew waiting.
嘿，我每個禮拜都這樣呢，還加上 三個攝像機和所有劇組人員等著我
So, Joey, what are you gonna do for us?
那，喬伊，你要表演什麼呢?
I will be doing a dramatic reading of one of Emma's books.
我會邊讀艾瑪的書邊演出來
Oh, okay. Which one?
哇，好耶，哪一本?
Well, it's one of her favorites.
哇，她收藏的其中一個
"Riding the Storm Out: Coping With Postpartum Depression."
從暴風雨中脫險： 對抗產後的抑鬱症 咿--咿--咿
Love You Forever.
始終愛你
"Love You Forever, by Robert Munsch. Published by Firefly Books. Printed..
始終愛你，作者：羅柏.曼 螢火蟲出版社出版
in Mexico.
墨西哥印刷
A mother held her new baby and very slowly rocked him..
一個母親抱起他的嬰兒 慢慢的，往前搖，往後搖
back and forth, back and forth, back and forth.
往前搖，往後搖... 往前搖，往後搖...
And while she held him, she sang, 'I'll love you forever.
當母親抱著時，他唱了： 我會始終愛你
I'll like you for always. As long as I'm living..
我會一直喜歡你 只要我還活著
my baby you'll be.'"
你就是我的孩子
"And while he rocked her, he sang:
當母親抱著時，他唱了：
'I'll love you forever. I'll like you for always.
我會始終愛你，我會一直喜歡你
As long as I'm living..
只要我還活著
my baby you'll be.'"
你就是我的孩子
Oh, wow!
哇！
That was amazing.
哇，真的太棒了
Thank you so much for that gift.
真的非常感謝你的禮物
I was not ready for this today.
今天我心理沒有這個準備呢
- Amazing. Amazing. - Phoebe, I'm sorry.
- 太棒了，太棒了 -喔，菲比，抱歉
- Phoebe has prepared something as well. - That's right.
- 菲比也要表演給大家看 - 沒錯，
I prepared a song for Emma, from my heart to hers.
我準備了一首歌給艾瑪 直接從我心裡到她心裡
For there's no greater gift than the gift of music.
沒有比音樂更好的禮物了
Emma Your name poses a dilemma
「艾瑪」 「你的名字給我一個困境」
'Cause not much else rhymes with "Emma"
「和你名字押韻的少極了」
Maybe the actor Richard Crenna He played the commanding officer in Rambo
「也許僅有演員理查德·克裡納」 「他是演藍波的長官」
Happy birthday, Emma
「生日快樂，艾瑪」
Is that it?
就這樣?
No, of course not.
不，當然不是，還有--
No, I've also, you know, prepared a reading.
其他的-- 我也要朗讀
"Sex and the Single Mother."
性愛和單身母親
- "Finding your G-spot." - Oh, no, no, no!
- 查找性感帶的方法 - 不要啊
Hello, Emma. Happy 18th birthday.
嗨艾瑪, 祝你十八歲生日快樂
Right now, that seems so far away,17 years.
如果從現在算起，還有十七年之久呢
Yes. You'll be all grown up by then, and we'll be..
到時候你已經長大了，而到時候我們---
Well, your grandfather and I might not be here.
你公公和我都不在了
That's true. This message could be coming to you..
沒錯，這信息
from beyond the grave, Emma.
會是來自我們的墳墓裡
- After all, my parents died very young. - And my cholesterol's off the charts.
- 還有，我父母親很年輕就過世了 - 我的膽固醇還過高呢
Remember, Emma, heart disease kills women too.
艾瑪，請記得 女生也會因心臟病而死
Okay, cut! Great. Great. That was just..
好了，好了，這樣就夠了
- Yeah. - Oh, good.
- 噢！ - 哦，好的！
Ross, don't forget to get a shot of Emma's cake.
羅斯，別忘了要拍蛋糕
- It's in a box in the fridge. - Okay, sure.
- 在冰箱的盒子裡 - 好的，沒問題
You're gonna love this cake. I got it from a bakery in New Jersey, Carino's.
喔，你會喜歡這蛋糕 我從新澤西州的麵包店買來的，加理諾麵包店
Oh, my God, that place has the creamiest frosting!
喔，他們有全世界最好吃的奶油
I used to hitchhike there when I was a kid.
我小時候喜歡搭便車去那裡
Well, anyway, they make these great novelty cakes..
無論如何，他們做了很多種口味
in all different shapes. And if you give them a photo, they'll copy it in icing.
也很多種造型，如果你自己準備照片 他們還會放到蛋糕上
- Did you do a picture of Emma? - Yes. On a cake shaped like a bunny.
-那你一定放艾瑪的照片嘍 -當然，在一個兔子形的蛋糕
Rach? Does this bakery by any chance also bake..
瑞秋，這家店是不是剛好
erotic cakes?
也賣色情蛋糕?
Say, for bachelorette parties?
上面寫：給單身派對使用
Ross, what are you talking..? Oh, my God!
你在講什麼啊? 喔，我的天啊。
They put my baby's face on a penis!
他們還把 我女兒的臉放在「小弟弟」上
Now it's a party!
這才像派對嘛
Wait, you guys, this isn't funny.
喔，如果真有那麼好笑的話
If I wanted this cake to be a disaster, I would have baked it myself!
我也可以自己做這種形狀的啊
Is it okay that I still think it looks delicious?
啊，沒事，我還是認為很好吃
- Jack, look at this. - I know what you're thinking, Judy.
-傑克，你看看 -我知道你在想什麼
The resemblance is uncanny.
其相似程度非常驚人
I am this close to tugging on my testicles again.
我也差點再度拉我的蛋蛋
Ironically, that was the Maxim thing.
諷刺的是, 那和Maxim雜誌一樣.
No, no, this is not what I ordered, okay?
不是，不是，這不是我要訂的
I went all the way to New Jersey so that I could have the perfect cake..
我特地去新澤西州 只為了我女兒有完美的生日蛋糕
for my daughter's birthday. And I need a bunny cake right now!
還有，我需要兔子蛋糕。現在!!
Ask them if it would be faster if we cut the baby's face off the penis..
如果要快點的話，我們 可以從「小弟弟」上取出你的照片，
so we could put it on the bunny.
再貼到兔子蛋糕上
That is a weird sentence.
好像不是很適當
Oh, believe you me, I am going to bring this cake back.
我會把蛋糕換回去
I don't even want it in my home. Don't touch it!
甚至我不想有這種蛋糕在我家 喬伊，不要碰
I'm so confused!
我很疑惑啊!!!
Yes, I still want my daughter's picture, but on a bunny cake!
是的，我還是要我女兒照片 但是在兔子形狀的蛋糕上
Yellow cake, chocolate frosting with nuts!
黃色蛋糕，有奶油和花生!!!
To be fair, this one does have nuts.
說實在的，這上面沒有花生
Mon, it was nice of you to loan Rachel your car..
嗨，莫妮卡，你真好把車借給瑞秋
- so she could get the cake. - It was nice of her to pull my hair..
-為了她可以換蛋糕 -因為她一直拉我頭髮
till I dropped the key.
至到我給她鑰匙
Well, while we're waiting, you could tape your message to Emma..
你知道嗎，即然閒著 就先錄一段給艾瑪的...
for her 18th birthday, huh? Okay?
十八歲生日 好不好?
Hi, Emma. It's the year 2020.
嗨，艾瑪，現在是 2020 年
Are you still enjoying your nap?
你還在享受你的睡眠嗎?
We're Aunt Monica and Uncle Chandler, by the way.
我們是莫妮卡和錢德
You may not recognize us..
你可能不認識我們
because we haven't spoken to your parents in 17 years.
因為我們已經十七年了 沒有和你父母親講話
We used to be married.
我們本來已結婚
But then we missed a weekend away together, and things kind of unraveled..
但我們搞砸了 我們的一個週末，造成我們分開
because of you.
就是因為你!!!
- Happy birthday. - Thanks. Another good one.
-生日快樂!! -謝謝. 又一個有趣的胡扯
I can't believe I taped over my Big Brother audition for this.
我不能相信我竟然錄了這些.
Ross, Rachel promised it would be over by now.
羅斯, 瑞秋答應過這時候應該結束了
We seriously have to go if we want to get to Vermont.
我們如果要去佛蒙特現在該出發了
- The last train leaves in a half-hour. - And I have a massage client soon.
-我問過了，最後班次在半小時後 -你知道嗎，我有要按摩的客戶
You guys, just, please, a little bit longer.
嘿，大家，忍耐一下
I promise, Rachel will be back with the cake any minute.
瑞秋隨時會帶著蛋糕回來
Monica, remember the frosting, huh?
莫妮卡，記得該店的奶油味道嗎?
All right, five more minutes.
好，我再等五分鐘
Hello?
喂?
Oh, no, what happened?
發生什麼事?
Okay, okay, where are you?
好的，好的，你在哪裡?
Okay, I'll be right there.
我會過去的
Was that Emma? Is she up?
那是不是艾瑪? 她起來了嗎?
Rachel got pulled over for speeding.
瑞秋因為超速被攔下來
She forgot her license. I have to bring it to her.
她忘了帶車照，我得送過去
- If you're leaving, I'm definitely going. - Wait, if anybody gets to go, it's us!
-如果你要走，那我也得走 -等一下，如果有人要走那就是我們
We've been complaining the longest!
是我們抱怨最久的
No, wait, you guys. No, you can't leave.
等等，你們不能離開
Rachel already feels bad that the cake's messed up.
蛋糕的事已讓瑞秋很煩
How do you think she'll feel when she comes back and you're gone?
如果回來時發現大家不在 那她會怎麼覺得?
I don't know. You'll tell us on Monday.
我不知道，你禮拜一再告訴我吧
Joey, you're in charge, okay? You make sure nobody leaves.
喬伊，你負責這裡，要確認沒有人離開
Got it!
瞭解
Hey! Where do you think you're going?
嘿嘿嘿，你要去哪?
To the bathroom.
去洗手間啊
Well, the rest of you get comfortable, because we are gonna be here for a..
即然大家會待一段時間 請當做自己家裡--
- Wait, there's a window in there. - No! He's not getting away that easy!
-等等，洗手間裡有個窗戶... -不要讓他逃走
What are you doing? Get the hell out of here!
喂，你們幹什麼啊!! 快滾出去啊!!
Well, that one did not have Emma's face on it.
那個「小弟弟」上沒有艾瑪的照片
- No, it did not. - No.
-是，當然沒有 - 對。
Well, we'd better get going. It's late.
已經很晚了，我們真的要走了
Jack can't drive at night anymore. He has trouble staying in his lane.
傑克不能在晚上開車了
Last winter I went up on a church lawn and drove right through a manger scene.
去年冬天，我開車經過教堂的草地 然後撞上馬的食槽
The papers thought it was a hate crime.
報紙誤以為那是一個報仇計劃
- Anyway, it was lovely seeing you. - Okay.
-無論如何，很高興可以見到你們 -好的
- Bye. Bye, dear. - Nighty-night.
-再見 -晚安
- Nighty-night. - Bye.
-晚安 - 再見.
- How could you just let them leave? - Hey, hey, hey.
-喬伊，你怎麼可以讓他們離開? -嘿嘿
I'm not gonna mess with Jack. He's a great man. He fought for our country.
我不會和傑克過不去的 他是一個好人，為國家而戰
No, he didn't. He pretended to be a Quaker to get out of Korea.
他才沒有呢，他裝成貴格會教徒 才可以逃離韓國
Well, that's it. He's the last one to go. I'm locking you guys in.
夠了，他是最後一個離開的 我把門鎖上了
You do know I can just turn them the other way around, right?
你知道那個鎖是 可以從這裡面打開的
Oh, I forgot you used to live here.
喔，我忘了你以前住過這裡
- Hello? - Joey, it's Estelle.
-喂 -喬伊，我是你的經紀人 Estelle
- Hey. - So how'd your audition go today?
-嗨，你好 -你今天的試鏡如何?
- What audition? - The one I told you about last week.
-什麼試鏡? -上禮拜我和你說過的啊?
What? You never said anything about an audition.
什麼？你根本沒有說過任何試鏡!
Let me start over. I just got a call about an audition.
那我從頭說起，我剛接到你的試鏡通知
I think you can still make it.
你現在去還來得及
It's down at the Astor Theater, and you need to have a monologue prepared.
就在Aster戲院，還要自己帶獨白
A monologue? I don't have a..
獨白? 我沒有呢--
I got it.
喔，有了...
So I'm gonna take off.
那我要走了
- What? - No, wait! You don't get to leave.
-什麼？ - 不，等等，你不能離開
I've got a massage client waiting outside my door any minute.
我有按摩客戶等在我家門外呢
And we paid for a room that we're supposed to be in right now!
我們已經付錢給一個 我們現在應該住在裡面的房間
Well, okay, now..
好好
only one of us has to stay with Emma.
只要有一個人照顧艾瑪就行了
Okay, and as the person who realized that, I get to go.
因為是我剛發現這點的 所以我可以走了
No, no, no. No. No.
不行，不行
Let's figure out a fair way to decide who's staying.
那我們想一個較公平的 方法來決定誰要留下來
Oh, I got it.
喔，有了。
Okay, everyone pick a number from one to 10, all right?
大家選擇一到十的數字
Whoever gets the highest number gets to go first.
誰選到最大的數字可以先走
- Okay,10. - Okay, Monica picks 10. I call nine.
-好喔，我選「十」 -那我選「九」
Anyone else?
還有其他的嗎?
- No, let's just draw straws. - Okay.
-大家來抽籤吧?	 - 好。
Or we could flip a coin and multiply the answer..
或是可以用硬幣--
- I'm begging you to stop. - Right.
-拜託你，不要講話了 - 好。.
Okay, how about this? We got wind-up toys for Emma.
這樣好啦，我們從艾瑪的 生日禮物選一個發條玩具
We can make them race, and whoever comes in last stays.
拿來賽跑 跑最後的就要留下來
Yeah, let's do that!
好吧，就這樣
That sounds more fun than the thing we were gonna do in Vermont!
這好像和佛蒙特的事情比起來好玩多了!
- Okay, everybody, pick your toys! - Okay. I want the dolphin!
- 好，各位，開始選玩具吧。 -我要用那個海豚!!
- That's a bear! - I'm too excited!
-菲比，那是一隻熊 -抱歉，我太興奮了!!
Phoebe, you get the bear. Joey, you get the robot.
菲比，你用這只熊 喬伊，你用機器人
- Oh, yeah. - And Chandler and I get the dog.
-哦，好的。 -錢德和我就用這隻狗吧
And the race is going to go from here to here.
比賽就要開始了... 從這裡，到這裡
Now, the one who comes in last stays!
誰最後一名的，要留下來!!
Okay, ladies and gentlemen, wind your toys.
各位先生及女士，捲好你的發條
- Okay. On your mark, get set, go! - Go! Go!
-準備了嗎?預備，開始！ -快，快!!
Come on, robot!
不要停!機器人！
What are you barking at?
你在幹什麼啊?!!?
Well, how is that gonna help?
那個動作有什麼作用嗎!?!?
I bought you! How did I forget that that's all you do?
我買了你! 我竟忘了你只會這個動作?
Way to go, robot!
好樣的, 機器人!
Good job, Alan.
幹的好，熊熊
- Hey, good race, you guys. - Yeah, see you later.
-真是一個好比賽 -是啊，那就再見嘍
No. No, no. Wait.
不，不，你們等一下
We didn't lose.
我們沒有輸呢
The rules clearly stated that the last one to cross the finish line was the loser.
規定是說，最後跑到終點才是輸家
Well, our dog never crossed the finish line. So technically..
那我們的狗，沒有跑到終點，所以--
They left.
他們已經走了!
There isn't time to go to the bakery. We're gonna come home.
你知道嗎? 根本沒時間去麵包店 所以我們現在回家了
Everybody left?
大家已經走了?
All right. Well, just tell Emma that we'll be there as soon as we can. Bye.
好喔，告訴艾瑪 我們會盡快回家，再見
- Rachel! - Oh, God, sorry!
-瑞秋!!! -喔，天啊，抱歉
I can't believe they gave you a ticket. You're such a good driver.
真不敢相信，他們給了你一個罰單 你真是一個好駕駛人
- Emma's awake. - Yeah?
-艾瑪起來了 -是喔?
I can't believe this.
真不敢相信
This is her first birthday, she's awake, we're not even there.
在她的一歲生日 她醒來時，我們不在
Everybody left. We still have this stupid obscene cake.
大家也已經走了 還加上這個爛蛋糕!!!
Hey, maybe I can fix that. You know, try to turn it into something else.
嘿，也許我可以弄好這蛋糕 試試看，改成別的形狀嘛
Oh, don't even bother.
已經無所謂了
We've already ruined her first birthday.
我們已經毀了她的第一個生日
And do you know how important these early experiences are, Ross? Very!
你不知道這些早期的經驗 對她有多重要嗎，羅斯?非常重要
According to the back cover of that book that you gave me.
依照你給我的那本書背面
Rach, she's not gonna remember this.
瑞秋，她不會記得這些
I guess.
也許吧
Oh, I just had such an idea of what this day would be like, you know?
喔，我本來想像今天是怎樣的一天
Emma laughing..
艾瑪在笑
and everybody gathered around her cake, singing "Happy Birthday."
大家圍繞著蛋糕唱「生日快樂」
And then we would all.. Hey, get out of the road, you stupid student driver!
然後--嘿，不要擋本姑娘的路 笨笨的初學者!!!
They have to learn.
他們總要學這點
- Hey. - What?
-嘿 -什麼?
This is not bad.
這不錯嘛
Oh, my God. Look, you made it into a bunny. How did you do that?
喔，天啊。你把它變成兔子了 你怎麼弄的，羅斯?
Well, I just made these two things cheeks.
我把這邊改成臉頰
And then I split this to make ears.
這部分再分兩邊，變成耳朵
Well, I am very impressed.
喔，我非常感動呢
Some can sing, some can dance.
有些人會唱歌，些人會跳舞
I, apparently, can turn phallic cakes into woodland creatures.
我顯然 可以把「小弟弟」改成兔子蛋糕
Now, another way to organize your stuffed animals is by size.
還有另外一種方法來整理玩具 就是按照大小
I'm sorry, is this a game for Emma or for Monica?
對不起，這是給艾瑪 玩的遊戲，或是給莫妮卡?
Game?
遊戲?
Emma, do you even know it's your birthday today? You're 1.
你知道今天是你生日嗎? 你是一。
One year old. That's little.
就是一歲，這麼小
That's my girl.
哈，這我的女兒??
That's how old you are.
這就是你的年齡
Did I teach her that? Did I just impart wisdom?
是我教她的嗎? 或是我傳授智能給她?
I want one.
喔，我也想要有一個
Me too.
我也是
There's no one around. Why don't we just take this one?
這裡沒人，乾脆我們帶走她，好嗎?
- And head to Canada. - I was kidding.
-然後跑去加拿大? -我在開玩笑
I wasn't. Let's get going.
我可沒有呢!! 快點出發吧
- Hey, are Ross and Rachel back? - No, not yet.
-嘿，羅斯和瑞秋回來了嗎? -還沒有呢
- Oh, good, I didn't miss the party. - What about your massage client?
-喔，好耶，我沒錯過派對嘛 -那你的按摩客戶呢?
I just felt so bad missing this. So I just slipped him a little something, you know.
我覺得很內疚如果錯過這派對 所以我給他一些東西
As long as I'm back in five or six hours, it'll be all right.
五或六個小時後再做也可以
Okay.
好！
If Ross and Rachel ask, I've been here the whole time. The whole time.
嘿，如果羅斯，瑞秋問起我， 說我一直待在這裡
I've been here the whole time.
我一直待在這裡的
Joey, we just saw you come in. You ran past us on the stairs.
喬伊，我們剛看到你進來 而且你跑上來時，在樓梯經過我們
I don't care that you left. I'm just glad that you're here. Thanks, you guys.
我不管你有沒有離開 我很高興你們現在在這裡，謝謝大家
Hey, guys, come on. You gotta see what Emma just did.
嘿，大家過來 你們應該看看艾瑪剛做了什麼
- What? - Emma, how old are you?
- 什麼? -艾瑪，你幾歲?
How old are you today?
你今天幾歲?
Emma, that's right. You're that many.
對了， 艾瑪就是一歲
Oh, my God, our daughter's a genius.
喔，天啊，我們女兒是一個天才
- This means.. - No! No science camp!
-這表示-- -不要有科學的說教了
Damn it! I'll put a candle on the cake.
喔，真是的，我把蠟燭放到蛋糕上
Oh, and, Emma, look at your stuffed animals lined up so neatly.
喔，艾瑪，看看你的娃娃 排的如此整齊
Thanks.
謝謝
Okay, here we go.
好了，要開始了
Emma's first birthday cake.
這是艾瑪第一個生日蛋糕
Go ahead, Emma, blow out the candle.
快吹啊，吹滅蠟燭
Come on, Emma. You can do it.
快，艾瑪，你能做到的。
- What's wrong? Are you okay? - Oh, yeah, nothing.
-怎麼啦，你還好吧? -喔，沒事
These are happy tears.
這是快樂的眼淚
This is just what I wanted.
這就是我想要的
Hey, you made it into a bunny.
嘿，蛋糕已變成兔子形狀的
What is wrong with me? It looked more delicious when it was a penis.
喔，我怎麼啦， 為什麼 「小弟弟」的形狀時看來比較好吃
- Okay, you ready? - Yeah.
-好，準備好了嗎? -是的
- And record. - Okay.
-那，開始錄了 -好。
Big Brother audition. Take one.
試音.
I guess you could say I'm kind of a player.
我猜你會說 我是一個演員..
Okay. Let's..
好了.讓我...
- Let's just try that again. - Okay.
- 我們再試一次. - 好的.
Hi, Emma. Well, your first birthday is over, and..
嗨，艾瑪，你的生日剛結束了 而且--
Go! Go! Come on!
快啊，快啊
快啊，快點
Go! Go, Alan! Run, you hairy bastard!
熊熊，快跑啊 你這只笨熊